<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Michael T. Stobb</title><link>https://stobb.org/</link><description>Recent content on Michael T. Stobb</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.154.2</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://stobb.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://stobb.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an associate professor of Data Science at Coe College in Cedar Rapids, Iowa. Before the move to Iowa, I did my PhD in Applied Mathematics at the University of California in Merced, and a BA and MS, also in Applied Math, at Humboldt State University in Arcata, California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="research-interests"&gt;Research Interests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While continually expanding, my current interests include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uncertainty Quantification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning (e.g., Deep Learning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High Performance Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematical Modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematical Biology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://stobb.org/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/contact/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="on-sabbatical-spring-2026"&gt;On Sabbatical Spring 2026&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="address"&gt;Address&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coe College&lt;br&gt;
1220 1st Ave NE&lt;br&gt;
Cedar Rapids, IA 52402&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="email"&gt;Email&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="mailto:mstobb@coe.edu"&gt;mstobb@coe.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="mailto:michael@stobb.org"&gt;michael@stobb.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://stobb.org/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/cv/</guid><description>My Curriculum Vitae</description></item><item><title>Personal</title><link>https://stobb.org/personal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/personal/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I live in &lt;strong&gt;Cedar Rapids, Iowa&lt;/strong&gt; with my wife, son, daughter, and one cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stobb Family" loading="lazy" src="https://stobb.org/images/stobb_family.jpg" title="The Stobb Family!"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="some-of-my-current-hobbies-include"&gt;Some of my current Hobbies include&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ukulele&lt;/strong&gt;: Making music with something smaller than a piano. Check out &lt;a href="https://ukuguides.com"&gt;ukuguides.com&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Woodworking&lt;/strong&gt;: Furniture especially, similiar to the &lt;a href="https://paulsellers.com/"&gt;Paul Sellers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://stobb.org/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/research/</guid><description>&lt;div class="columns-container"&gt;
&lt;div class="column"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="uncertainty-quantification"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncertainty Quantification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inputs for most of our mathematical models are inherently uncertain, either from a lack of knowledge about the details of a system or the intrinsic uncertainty of the underlying variables. Fortunately, this does not usually keep us from using models in practical applications to make predictions or infer behavior. It does, however, require some user choice for the unknown values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncertainty Quantification (UQ) is the science of understanding and systematically accounting for these various unknowns. The figure shown above is an illustration of a very common uncertainty propagation framework, where unknown inputs are quantified as distributions which are used with the mathematical model (here a system of ODEs) via some method to propagate those uncertainties forward to quantities of interest. Here the graphic hints at the use of generalized Polynomial Chaos (gPC) to obtain an output distribution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://stobb.org/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/software/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="my-tools"&gt;My Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few examples of my code (those that I&amp;rsquo;m able to make publicly available) can be seen on my GitHub page. Some are just for fun (like the battleship simulator), while others were made for research purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://eventplacer.app"&gt;Event Placer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A free tool to schedule events into a limited number of rooms. Built with Coe Students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="recommended-software"&gt;Recommended Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I use and recommend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://julialang.org"&gt;Julia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A newish programming language first made available in 2012, Julia focuses on performance and efficiency without sacrificing clarity. Julia has a syntax that closely resembles Mathwork&amp;rsquo;s MATLAB, but is open source and freely available. More importantly, due to the central placement of multiple dispatch and a strong type system, Julia is able to achieve speeds close to native C (for some applications). While imperfect, Julia has almost solved the two-language problem in my work and has become my favorite language for coding.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://stobb.org/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/teaching/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="current-students"&gt;Current Students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are here looking for information on current classes, head over to &lt;a href="moodle.coe.edu"&gt;Moodle&lt;/a&gt; where all course content is located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="my-thoughts-on-teaching"&gt;My Thoughts on Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching is one of my life&amp;rsquo;s true passions. I believe that helping others learn (and learning how to learn!) is one of the unique joys in life. This page lists my thoughts on teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My teaching philosophy is based on the principle of an active partnership between instructors and students. I see the educator as being responsible for explaining/demonstrating new skills for multiple learning modalities, giving students opportunities to develop those skills for themselves, and allowing students to appropriately gauge their level of understanding to know when to seek out further assistance. Similarly, I see the student as needing to be receptive to new information, willing to work diligently to acquire new skills, and empowered to ask for help when needed. None of us are these things all the time, but my personal goal in teaching is to always inspire students to greater success by owning their own personal responsibility in the learning process. For more detailed information, see the page here on my &lt;a href="https://stobb.org/teaching_philosophy/"&gt;teaching philosophy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teaching Philosophy</title><link>https://stobb.org/teaching_philosophy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/teaching_philosophy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My teaching philosophy is grounded in creating an exciting and enthusiastic learning environment in which a strong and active partnership between educators and students can form. Whether in a classroom setting or privately during office hours, educators and students should be jointly invested in the learning enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoy my role as an educator, which I see as having three main responsibilities: 1) To provide engaging and accessible explanations of content with illustrative examples, 2) To give several opportunities for students to practice their new skills, both independently and with their peers, and 3) To provide appropriate metrics for students to gauge their own success.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Undergraduate Research</title><link>https://stobb.org/undergrad_research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stobb.org/undergrad_research/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have had the pleasure of working with several undergraduate students over the years. Here&amp;rsquo;s a short list of some of the projects we&amp;rsquo;ve worked on together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>